Michael Wester

(414) 380-3555 | mpwester@gmail.com

Software Engineer with over 13 years of professional experience in all aspects of the software development lifecycle. Range of experiences in green field projects, legacy applications, lightweight RESTful API's, Microservice based applications and stand-alone front-end clients. With a history of delivering on time quality software I am a proven leader, mentor, advocate and contributor.

Technical Expertise/Skills

Programming frameworks: Angular, Typescript, C#, React, Express, GraphQL

Testing frameworks: Jasmine, Jest, MSTest, XUnit, Selenium

Databases: SQL Server, Oracle, Redis, Cosmos DB, MongoDB, RedShift, Postgres, Snowflake, Gremlin

Cloud Services: Microsoft Azure and AWS

Tools: Azure Pipelines, AngularCLI, CircleCI, Octopus, JIRA, Jenkins, Github Workflows

Professional Experience

The Predictive Index, Remote Lead Engineer

Oct 2021 - Nov 2022

Global Experience initiative that consists of a team of engineers, a product designer, and a product manager to standardize UI components and user experience of the Predictive Index suite. This initiative consists of building a new Angular consumable library for other modules/micro-frontends to consume.

- Initial library setup and integration with Storybook.
- Integrate Angular Materials to replace existing infrastructure.
- Setup contribution guide allowing organization wide contribution.
- Manager of 3 direct reports.

GoPuff, Remote

Feb 2021 - Oct 2021

Software Engineer II

Forecasting Engineering initiative is designed to better forecast workload/orders helping to manage and predict resources needed to keep up with guaranteed delivery times. Developing a new Full Stack React/Express/GraphQL application deployed in a Docker container. The Forecasting application is designed to take the current manual processes with multiple variations and standardize metrics across the organization.

- Learning and developing best practices for new React/GraphQL development.
- Developed numerous styled components to bring consistent feel to the new application.
- Setup base infrastructure for new development, builds, release and standalone instances.

InvestCloud (formerly Advicent), Milwaukee, WI Senior Software Engineer

Jul 2019 – Jun 2020

Guided Retirement, a greenfield front-end project, application provides a quick overview and basic insight from Financial Advisors to their end clients about retirement planning. The Essentials project, a greenfield full stack project, provides a more robust solution allowing for a larger customer base to access great financial planning. Both solutions utilized an Angular frontend communicating with RestFUL micro service-based backend. Both are fully built and deployed utilizing Azure Pipelines and docker containers.

- One of 4 required Angular developers pull request approvers, ensuring quality code.
- Started the new Essentials Angular Front-end project from scratch.
- Developed and released two new greenfield applications.
- Functioned as team lead for 3 software engineers, 1 QA engineer and 1 automation engineer.

Michael Wester

(414) 380-3555 | mpwester@gmail.com

Finastra (formerly D+H), Mequon, WI Software Engineer

May 2016 - Jul 2019 Sep 2017 - Jul 2019

Point-of-Sale Mortgage system development engineer, enhancing the legacy application providing banks with a SaaS solution, enabling them the ability to provide and process mortgage applications online.

- Implemented features to comply with ADA (American Disability Act) in association with WCAG
- Implemented integration with 3rd party applications to provide integrations for mortgage options and rates.
- Transitioned from aging TFS infrastructure to decentralized VSTS with Git hosted on top.
- Transitioned to modern technologies and best practices.

Software Engineer - Dev Lead

May 2016 - Sep 2017

Development Lead of a small team, 3 software engineers, 2 QA engineers, 3 offshore-software engineers), on a new green field product, NLP (New Lending Platform). Composed of a Razer MVC/Angular 4 front-end paired with C# .NET backend API and being deployed utilizing Microsoft Azure and Octopus.

- One of 12 required pull request approvers, ensuring quality code.
- Developed multiple components and services to be consumed by our SPA and PWA.
- Implemented Angular animations to provide a stimulating overall User Experience.
- Implemented a new Angular Front end from beta to release candidate ending in Angular 4.

Blue Yonder (formerly JDA), Waukesha, WI Senior Consulting Software Engineer

May 2015 - Apr2016

Implantation Service - Developmental Services Engineer addressing identified gaps between our core software platform and the customer needs. Frequently requested gaps by multiple customers were worked to implement features inside of the core product warehouse management suite in addition to specific customers.

- Implement Voice enhancements introduced to the core product.
- Lead efforts collaborating with customers directly to meet their needs.
- Provided on-site support during customer go-lives to ensure the system is meeting the customer needs.

Iptor (formerly IBS AB), Brookfield, WI Software Developer

Nov 2013 - May 2015

Software development engineer looking to modernize the current Dynaman application from VB .NET monolithic application to AngularJS and C# API based application. Also was selected to spearhead a project to modernize and create integrations with 3rd party applications replacing SSIS with Java RESTful/SOAP web services.

- Developed Entity Framework RESTful API's for integration with internal and external systems.
- Implemented SOAP base Web Services for 3rd party integrations with the WMS.
- Helped lead development efforts modify core applications for S tier customers.

Michael Wester

(414) 380-3555 | mpwester@gmail.com

Blue Yonder (previously JDA previously RedPrairie), Waukesha, WI Dec 2009 – Nov 2013 Software Architect Intern/Senior Software Engineer/Technical Consultant Intermediate

Product Development Software Architect Intern working on new features and bug issues for our core product. Transitioned full time software engineer in our implementation services department and assisted in project implementations collaborating directly with customers to identify gaps between our product and their needs.

- Implemented new features to provide threaded session expiration in our core product.
- Worked on Johnson & Johnson, Georgia Pacific, Valspar and lead development efforts for MDL.
- Provided Analysis, Design, Implementation and Support for different phases of projects.

Education

University of Wisconsin – Milwaukee – Bachelor of Science in Computer Science